《永无止境》前情提要
Previously on Limitless...
我们每天给他吃一次药
We give him the pill once a day.
这药能提高他的认知能力
It enhances his cognition.
-五粒NZT  -这是做什么
- Five NZT pills. - What are those for?
随你所愿
Whatever you want.
我还有些额外的NZT  私房货
I might have a few extra NZT pills, my own stash.
我们之后一定会再谈这事
We are gonna talk about this later.
缝合得相当好
Pretty tidy stitch job.
-是联调局教你的吗  -是的
- The FBI teach you that? - Yes, it did.
瑞秋  我讲真的
Rach, I really mean it
真的别告诉任何人这件事  好吗
when I say don't tell anyone about this, okay?
谁也不说
Not anyone, ever.
桑兹杀了丽贝卡的父亲
Sands killed Rebecca's father.
我没能救我父亲
I couldn't help my father.
也许我能救你
Maybe I can help you.
不要对我说谎  永远不要
Just don't lie to me. Ever.
私藏NZT药片  5粒
"我想在这座不眠之城里醒来"
"I want to wake up in the city that never sleeps".
《New York, New York》
私藏NZT药片  4粒
法兰克·辛纳屈曾唱过这首歌
Frank Sinatra once sang that,
二十世纪流行音乐人物
现在已是陈词滥调了
and now it's cliché.
但是当事情变得糟糕时
But when things get bad--
我想说得知桑兹杀了丽贝卡的父亲
and I would say that living with the knowledge
就算很糟糕
Sands killed Rebecca's father qualifies as bad--
令我欣慰的是  我能走出门
it's comforting to know that I can walk out any door,
不管夜色多深  纽约依旧不眠
any hour of the night, and New York is still going.
经NZT强化的大脑可有的忙呢
Plenty to keep an NZT-enhanced mind occupied.
所以我来到了这里
That's kind of how I wound up here.
胡子
Beard.
胡子  那人有胡子吗
Beard. The guy had a beard?
不是  他是说那人脖子上有纹身  联调局的
No. He's saying the guy had a neck tattoo. FBI.
素描师有来吗
Uh, do you have a sketch artist on hand?
有  马蒂
Yeah. Marty?
马蒂  介不介意让我来画
Hey, Marty. Do you mind if I take a stab at this?
多谢
Thanks very much.
我知道你想干什么
I know what you're doing.
布莱恩·芬奇  你不是这些人想要的英雄
Brian Finch, not the hero the people want,
也不是他们需要的人
or need for that matter.
你到底来这里做什么
What are you even doing out here?
我要了结这个案子
I'm about to close this case.
我懂  你很擅长查案
Look, I get it. You're good at this.
你也许喜欢通过做好事来忘记所有坏事
And you may like that doing good helps you forget all the bad.
但你知道自己其实在做什么吗
But you know what you're really doing?
你在躲避的那些麻烦始终还是会找上门的
Is ducking a bunch of trouble that's gonna find you anyway.
丽贝卡·哈里斯来电
忽略
你迟早得对她撒谎的
You're gonna have to lie to her sooner or later.
你很擅长素描吧
You're pretty good at that, huh?
没错
Yeah.
交给你了
There you go.
警用广播
发现尸体
接到一起可疑犯罪  在大码头公园处
We got a 10-10, body of a male in his 20s
发现一具二十多岁的男性尸体
found in Grand Ferry Park.
各单位请回应
All units please respond.
你在吃洋葱圈吗
Are you eating Funyuns?
这不是违反规定...
Doesn't that defy the rules of...
今晚不守规矩的不止你一个
You're not the only rebel tonight.
一直在回避丽贝卡
This whole avoiding Rebecca thing...
老兄
Dude.
我该怎么做
What am I supposed to do?
我在她身边时  满脑子想的都是
You know, when I'm around her, all I can think about is
我知道是桑兹杀了她爸爸
how I know that Sands murdered her dad.
而这个凶手又正好是保住我小命的人
That the person who killed him is the same one keeping me alive.
-但我能告诉她吗  不能  -不能
- But can I tell her that? No. - No.
因为那意味着你得告诉丽贝卡
Because that would mean you would have to tell Rebecca
你是摩拉参议员安插在联调局里的内鬼
that you are Senator Morra's mole in the FBI.
也就是说你要失去
Which means losing, let's see,
酶和免疫力
the enzyme and your immunity.
还有我的自由和小命
And my freedom, my life.
而且就算你找到办法避开所有麻烦
And even if you found some way to dodge all that,
你也只能回去做个普通的布莱恩
you'd have to go back to being just Brian.
面对现实吧
And let's face it.
到时你会想念我的吧
You'd miss me, wouldn't you?
所以我要告诉你  拒丽贝卡于千里之外
So I'm telling you, pushing Rebecca away
并不是处理办法
is not the way to handle this.
我没这么做
That's not what I'm doing.
丽贝卡·哈里斯来电
老兄
Dude.
你可以忽视她  但你不能忽视我
You can ignore her, but you can't ignore me.
拒接
拒接  接听
奇怪了
Huh. That's weird.
纽约市
-你有所发现吗  -有
- Did you find something? - Yeah.
这把是市政府分发的钥匙
This is a city government-issued key.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
有一次
One time,
我记住了整个纽约市政府的在线机构名录
I memorized the whole NYC government directory online.
这把钥匙以97开头
And that key starts with a nine-seven,
指的是建筑局
which is the Department of Buildings,
后面跟着的1  特指的是
followed by a one, which specifically means
曼哈顿许可审批办公室
the Manhattan Permit Approvals Office.
也许你该把调查方向转到那里
So, maybe you should move your investigation there.
真是个卓有成效的夜晚
Let's just say it was a very productive night.
城市的活力暂时让我转移了视线
While the energy of the city temporarily took my mind off things,
但我是对的
I was right.
或者另一个布莱恩是对的
Or the other Brian was right.
我知道无法一辈子躲着丽贝卡
I knew I couldn't avoid Rebecca forever.
我的潜意识不会让我这么做
My subconscious just wouldn't let me.
布莱恩  你在搞什么
Brian, what the hell?!
无所谓了
Never mind.
我在纽约警局有熟人
I know people at the NYPD.
你以为他们不会告诉我
You think that they're not gonna tell me
我的顾问在到处亮他的徽章吗
my consultant is running around flashing his badge?
这个嘛
Well...
你为什么一直不接我电话
Why haven't you been answering my calls?
我手机没电了
Well, my phone's dead.
怪事了
That's weird.
你下了班还吃NZT吗
Are you on NZT when you're off-duty?
我们说过的
We've talked about this.
严格来说  我正在工作  丽贝卡
Well, technically, I am working, Rebecca.
只是没在为你工作而已
I'm just not working for you.
-快看那边  -得了吧
- Look over there. - Nice try.
-不顶用  -不  我说真的
- Not gonna work. - No, no, I'm serious.
怎么回事
What's going on?
应急发电机已启用  请节约用电
Emergency generators are in use. Please conserve all power.
麦克  你来为我提神的吗
Mike, what? You are here to pick me up?
是的
Yup.
-我们在大会议室集合  -马上就来
- We're assembling in the bullpen. - Be right there.
私藏NZT药片  4粒
私藏NZT药片  5粒
你要再吃一粒吗
You're gonna double your dose?
我希望你不要跟别人说...
Listen, I really appreciate you not saying anything to... you know.
我们会谈这事的
We are gonna talk about this.
有两个独立的地区目前受到停电影响
We have two distinct areas that are currently affected by the blackout.
金融区在凌晨四点最早受到影响
The Financial District took the first hit at 0400 hours.
有关部门在处理通常会发生的混乱情况
Authorities are dealing with the usual mess--
困在地铁和电梯里的人
people trapped in subways, elevators,
以及可能会发生的情况
as well as the what-ifs.
如果备用电源出故障  医院全黑了怎么办
You know, what if the backup generator fails and the hospitals go dark
或者信号接收塔坏了  或者水不流了
or the cell tower goes down or the water stops running?
因此在东北片区
So, in the northeast...
嗨亲们  有电吗  闪电表情
没电  汤米不用上学  真棒...
我们在新泽西  傻瓜  这儿有电
是啊  但那里还是新泽西  我这儿没电
妈  你和爸那边呢
这理有店
妈  我们说过了  要用自动更正
对不起  我打开了
电也来了  你们要回家来吗
城里会乱作一团的  瑞秋和卡梅伦
我让麦克和艾克来接你们
带你们去韦斯切斯特
豆子汤表情
Pea soup emoji.
她意思肯定是要做饭
还是你们要看《驱魔人》
瑞秋  卡梅伦  还有两位
瑞秋
别和联调局的那位陪同乱搞好吗
等等  太晚了
中指表情  混蛋
叫你们来  是因为得认识到
You're here because we have to acknowledge
我们的金融命脉首先受到停电影响
that the blackout hit our financial lifeline first.
中国  俄罗斯等国的国力足以发起网络攻击
Cyber is working on an angle that countries like China and Russia
网络处正从这个角度着手调查
are powerful enough to actually launch a cyber attack
他们的网络攻击可以将我们打回中世纪
that will basically knock us back to the Dark Ages.
我不这么看
Mm, yeah. I don't know.
布莱恩  你有想法吧
Brian, you have a thought.
有
I do.
实际上
As a matter of fact, um,
我们现在还有电
while we still have power,
我觉得"犯人"另有其人
I'd like to propose an alternative offender.
来吧
Come on up.
好的
Okay.
深红色代表我们市
So, uh, dark red indicates our city's
耗电最多的地区
highest level of energy consumption.
消耗最多的在这里和这里
The largest consumer being here and here.
尽管这两个地区在地理位置上
Now, even though these two areas seem
看似没什么联系
geographically disparate,
它们实际上被风联系了起来
they are, in fact, connected by the wind.
停电是顺着全市自然风流推进的
Now, the power outages are following the natural citywide gust flow.
我环境科学拿的是D-好嘛
I got a D-minus in environmental science, by the way.
勉强过关  但及格还是及格啊
It was a real squeaker, but, you know, passing is passing.
布莱恩  你父母肯定很骄傲
Brian, Brian, your parents must have been very proud.
没错  好吧  看这个
They really were. All right, watch this.
气流堵在城市里面
Drafts get stuck inside the city walls,
然后突然加速越过高楼大厦
and then slingshot up and over the high-rises.
你们能看到
And you can see, it goes
气流刚好从金融区跑到市中心
right from the Financial District up to Midtown.
你是指断电和天气有关吗
So you're saying the blackout is weather related?
我是指根据规律
Oh, I'm saying that based on the pattern,
无论是什么导致断电
whatever's causing the blackouts
都可能被风扩散  但你也知道
might be getting blown around by the wind, but, you know,
我得前往本地发电厂确认情况
I'd have to confirm by visiting local power plants, and...
当然我们仍然应该排除
And we should still rule out the possibility
网络战争的可能性
of cyber warfare, of course.
好吧
All right.
去吧
Go.
-好  -佩吉特探员和网络处合作
- Okay. - Agent Paget will coordinate with Cyber.
鲍伊探员和专案组的人合作
Agent Boyle will deal with the task force here on the floor.
我开车送你
I'll give you a lift.
你要去吗
You're coming?
有问题吗
Is that a problem?
不  我只是  不太清楚
Uh, no, I just... I don't know.
这只是个大胆的猜想
It's kind of a wild guess.
我不想浪费你时间
I don't want to waste your time.
但你之前都成功了
Well, I've seen those pan out before.
你可以在路上解释
You can explain it on the way.
我们应该告诉麦克和艾克
We should let Mike and Ike know.
我已经派他们去执行另外的任务
Oh, I actually kind of sent them on a mission of their own.
伙计  你到底在干什么
Man, what in the hell are you doing?
没什么
Nothing.
你在打扮
You're primping.
我没在打扮
I'm not primping.
像孔雀一样
Like a peacock.
想打扮帅点
Got to look good
赢得芬奇小妹的芳心吧
to win over little sister Finch.
得了吧  已经赢得了
Oh, please. That ship already came in.
说啊
Well, do tell.
我们一直在发短信
Yeah, we've been, um... texting.
虽然主要是...我在发
Which is mainly... you know, me texting.
她没回你短信
She's not texting you back.
你发了多少短信
How many texts have you sent?
表情包算吗
I mean, do Bitmojis count?
你好
Oh, hi.
-你好  -你好  瑞秋  你好
- Hi. - Hi, Rachel. Hi.
-谢谢你来接我  -不谢
- Thanks for picking me up. - Yeah.
要走了吗...
Are we going or just...?
-系安全带  -走了
- Buckle up. - Yeah.
发电机运转正常
Generator's operational.
我让手下反复检查过了
I've had my guys check and recheck.
涡轮叶片完全没问题
Nothing wrong with the turbine blades.
转子运转正常
The rotor is moving.
定子正常
The stator is good.
完全说不通
It doesn't make any sense.
应该有电啊
We should be hot.
工程师待命
Engineer, please stand by.
实压测试
Actual pressure test.
你们听到了吗
You guys hear that?
莫里斯
Hey, Maurice.
电力没从发电机里出来
So the electricity's not making it out of the generator.
没进入输电线
It's-it's not reaching the power lines.
没错  消失得无影无踪了
Exactly. It's just disappearing into thin air.
你能打开它吗
Can you open it up?
行  退后
Sure. Step back.
你在找什么
What are you looking for?
好吧
Well...
如果是经风传播的
Well, if it was carried by the wind,
肉眼可能看不到
it might be something we can't see with the naked eye.
能借我紫外灯吗
Do you mind if I borrow that black light?
请便
Be my guest.
来  退后
Here, step back.
那到底是什么
What the hell is it?
反正是有机体
Whatever it is, it's organic.
但这能造成断电吗  谢谢
Could that be causing the blackout though? Thank you.
我能跟你谈会儿吗
Can I talk to you for a minute?
我们得打给纳兹
We have to call Naz.
这可能是某种生物袭击
This could be some kind of biological attack.
没错
Yeah.
要知道我昨晚看到了
You know, I saw this last night.
你私自行侠仗义的时候吗
Out on your Capeless Crusade?
受害人身上也有这种发光的东西
This glowy stuff, it was on a murder victim.
他手上全是
It was all over his hands.
感觉有某种联系
I mean, it's got to be connected somehow.
所以你违法的行侠仗义之举
Oh, so your illicit, illegal escapades,
也不是毫无收获嘛
they weren't for nothing.
我还是做了点好事
I also do some good, you know.
这座城市谢谢你
And the city thanks you,
但这也不能为你的行为开脱
but... it doesn't make what you did right, or legal,
我也不会放任你
or okay with me.
你想不想跟进这个线索
You want to follow up on this lead or not?
跟进吧
Yes, lead on.
我们去了路易斯·瓦格斯的工作地点
So we headed to the workplace of Luis Vargas,
就是手发光的遇害保安
the dead security guard with the glowing hands.
纽约市建筑局
The New York City Department of Buildings
就是管理建筑物的建筑的部门
is the department that regulates the building of, well, buildings.
我在那里碰到了新朋友
Which is where we ran into my new friend,
赫尔南德斯警探
Detective Hernandez.
布莱恩·芬奇
Brian Finch.
白天也打击罪犯啊
The man fights crime by day, too.
赫尔南德斯警探  这是丽贝卡·哈里斯探员
Detective Hernandez, meet Agent Rebecca Harris.
谢谢你们同意我们昨晚借用你们的大神
Thanks for letting us borrow your golden boy last night.
不客气
Pleasure.
有什么事
So what's up?
我昨晚发现了很奇怪的东西
Well, last night, I noticed something really weird.
路易斯·瓦格斯尸体上有橙绿相间的物质
It was like a green and orange substance on Luis Vargas's body.
我觉得可能与断电有关
I think it may be connected to the blackout.
你们有不寻常的发现吗
Did you guys notice anything unusual here?
十八层有盏灯坏了
I mean, there was a broken lamp on the 18th floor,
但就目前看来
but far as we could tell,
主档案室
十八层
应该是在黑暗中被打翻了
it could've been knocked over in the blackout.
没丢东西
Nothing's missing.
那里不是存放着城市建筑的设计图吗
Isn't that where they store the blueprints for city buildings?
楼层指南上写着
Saw it on the directory.
我能看看吗
You mind if we take a look?
好吧
Cool.
-电梯没电了吧  -是的
- Elevators are out, aren't they? - Yep.
希望你们体力够
Hope you packed extra lungs.
我得加大有氧运动量
I've got to up my cardio.
你觉得呢  动感单车行吗
What do you think, spinning?
你做动感单车吗
Do you spin?
我可以一整晚追着你跑
I chase you around all night.
平心而论
Hey, you know, to be fair,
如果我昨晚没服NZT出去
we wouldn't even be following this lead--
等等  我们本来不会找到这条线索
hang on-- if I hadn't gone out last night on NZT.
如果你希望我为了一条
If you expect me to thank you for a lead
让我爬十八层的线索谢谢你...
that took me up 18 flights of stairs...
只是你发过誓不会再囤NZT药片了
It's just, you swore you would stop hoarding NZT pills.
我没囤了
I have.
那是最后一片
Okay, that was my last one.
还有这一片
Well, and this one.
麦克给我的
The one Mike gave me.
你保证你没对我说谎吗
You promise you're not lying to me?
我们是六岁小孩吗
What are we, six years old?
我保证  行吗
I promise, okay?
没其他药片了
No more extra pills.
私藏NZT药片  5粒
私藏NZT药片  4粒
这里有文件
Well, files here.
那里有文件
Files there.
你想分头找吗  这样快点
You want to split up, cover more ground?
行
Yeah.
你也许在想我在找什么
You might be wondering what I'm looking for.
我也是
So am I.
但我至少有个想法
But I at least have a theory:
有人闯进来找东西
someone broke in here searching for something.
但他们在找什么呢
But what were they after?
他们的归档系统简直是文员的噩梦
I mean, their filing system was a clerical nightmare,
但我把归错档和放错地方的文件整理好后
but after I sorted out the documents that were misfiled, or misplaced...
有个空抽屉很显眼
...there was one empty drawer that stood out,
像最近被翻查过
one that seemed recently raided.
219  东五十三大街
海龟湾五十三大街的一栋大楼设计图
Blueprints for a building on 53rd Street in Turtle Bay.
那里藏着什么  为了它非得杀死保安呢
What was there that was worth murdering a guard for?
这一切和停电又有什么关系
And how did all this relate to the blackout?
丽贝卡
Rebecca?
Rebecca?!
赫尔南德斯探长  怎么了
Detective Hernandez, what's going on?
先生  请站在原地
Sir, please hold right there.
-你是布莱恩·芬奇吗  -是
- Are you Brian Finch? - Yeah.
阳性
He's positive.
-你得跟我们走  -什么鬼
- You need to come with us. - What the hell?
基于联邦法规第42号法令第70条
Under 42 CFR 70,
我们要将你隔离
we're placing you into quarantine.
你接触了可疑物质
You came into contact with a suspicious substance.
什么  发电厂里的东西吗  到底是什么啊
What, the stuff from the power plant? What was it?
尚未确定
Undetermined.
什么意思
Well, what does that mean?
意思是来源不明
It means it came from an unknown origin.
-你俩都接触了  -好好好
- You've both been exposed. - Okay, okay, okay, okay.
疾病预防控制中心
还记得你今天说要载我一程吗
Remember when you offered to give me a ride today?
我本来想拒绝  可你非得坚持
And I was like, "Nah," And you were like, "I insist."
我猜你现在后悔了吧
I'm guessing you regret that decision now.
你说对了
You're not wrong.
偏偏今天被一起关在一个塑料房子里
Of all days to get sealed up in a plastic bubble together.
我意思是  你为了昨晚还有药的事生气
I just mean 'cause you're annoyed about last night and the pills.
这事我们已经说清楚了
We cleared that up.
-除非你还是没说实话  -当然不是
- Unless you're still lying to me. - I'm not.
-那就没事了呗  -那就好
- Then we're good. - Good.
我手机没电了
My phone's dead.
能借你的用用吗
Here, can I borrow yours?
路易斯·瓦格斯的案子还得调查
Just got to do some research on the Luis Vargas case.
这有一对"幸运儿"
Well, here's a lucky pair.
我叫斯特金·里德  天体物理学家
I'm Sturgeon Reid, astrophysicist.
今天我和疾病预防控制中心
Today, I'm working in tandem with the CDC
合作调查你们在发电厂遇到的物质
to take a look at the substance that you encountered at the power plant.
为什么天体物理学家会和疾控中心合作
Why is an astrophysicist working with the CDC?
今天我们发现了什么
What did we discover today?
官方还未确定
Officials are not yet sure,
伊恩·马歇尔
但"有生源说"大家都听过对吧
but panspermia, yeah?
认为地球上的生命起源于地外微生物
地球上的生命来自
The idea that life on Earth was seeded
我们究竟感染了什么
What exactly were we exposed to?
其他星球...
from other planets, other places...
麻烦关掉电视好吗
Would you turn that off, please?
外星生命...
...extraterrestrial life...
目前只知道是一种细菌
We know that it is a bacterium,
似乎直接
which appears to be feeding directly
以发电厂发的电为食
off the electricity generated by the power plant.
这并非第一种以电为食的细菌
It's not the first bacterium to do this,
但该物种十分独特
but this species is unique.
独特
Unique?
来自外太空那种独特吗
As in... from outer space?
我们在一艘昨天经过象限仪座流星雨下的
We found traces of the bacterium on a cargo ship
货船上发现了该细菌的痕迹
that passed under the Quadrantids meteor shower yesterday.
所以该物种的起源有可能是...
So it's possible that the origins of this species could be...
来自外星
Alien?
太赞了
This is awesome.
等会儿  我们不会死  对吧
Wait, we're not gonna die, are we?
你们打算怎样阻止细菌传播
What's the plan to stop the bacteria from spreading?
因为它以电为食
Since it's feeding off electricity,
我们希望通过切断曼哈顿的供电让它饿死
we're hoping to starve it by shutting down all the power in Manhattan.
城市肯定会一团糟
That's going to be chaos.
我们还要在这儿待多久
And how long do we have to stay here?
因为你们是直接接触者
Well, since you've had direct exposure,
所以我建议你们留下来接受观察
I've recommended you stay in observation.
如果你们感到不舒服就按铃叫工作人员
Alert the attendant if you feel ill.
但往好的方面想
But look on the bright side.
你们有可能创造历史
You could be making history.
这一切太蹊跷了
I don't know about all this.
什么意思
What do you mean?
我不知道
I don't know.
能借下你的手机吗
Can I borrow your phone?
要不然就玩猜字游戏
Or we could play charades.
谢谢
Thank you.
你爱听哪个电台
What's your, uh, what's your station?
都可以
Anything's good.
我不太听广播
I don't really listen to the radio.
看样子我们能及时离开这里了
Looks like we're getting out of here just in time, huh?
-我不想走  -快  快
- I don't want to. - Come on, come on.
谢谢你们
Hey, thanks for this, by the way.
你也知道有个冷得抓狂的五岁小孩有多烦人
You can imagine what it's like to have a cold, stir-crazy five-year-old.
不  我想要我的...
No, I want my...
把包给我  我们得带上包
Give me the bag. All right, we need the bag.
包在你那儿吗
You have the bag?
请进
Come on.
真高兴你们没事...
Oh, I'm so glad you're... I'm so glad you're okay.
小可爱
Hi, doll.
宝贝儿
Hi, honey.
真高兴你们来了  我们很担心
Oh, we're so glad you got here. We were getting worried.
他们是谁
Who's that?
是他们带我们出城的  态度好点
They got us out of the city. Be nice.
谢谢你们照顾我的孩子
Thanks for taking care of my kids.
应该的  先生  这是我们的荣幸
Of course, sir. It was... it was our pleasure.
我想你们现在该回去了吧
Well, I assume you'll be going back now.
走好
Good luck.
其实我们接到的命令是留下来
Actually, our orders are to stay
直到事情解决
until everything's been cleared up.
谁的命令
Orders from whom?
您儿子  先生
Your son, sir.
布莱恩
Brian.
如果会打扰的话  我们可以在外面等
We can wait outside, if that's easier.
没有  当然没有
Well, no, of course not.
外面太冷了  快进来
It's freezing. Uh, come in.
丹尼斯正在做午餐
Dennis is just getting lunch.
我要无谷蛋白的
I'm gluten-free.
海龟湾
Turtle Bay.
五十三街的第二大道至第三大道段
The address is on 53rd between 2nd and 3rd.
你知道我们很忙吧
You do realize we're kind of busy here.
我又不是让你给我买彩虹糖  鲍伊
Yeah, I'm not asking you to go get me some Skittles, Boyle.
我确信这很重要
I know this is important.
丢失的那份设计图
Look, the missing blueprints
是一栋商业大厦的
were for some kind of commercial building,
我在网上查找时发现
and when I looked online,
大楼地面以上部分的居住者都很普通
all of the occupants from the ground up were pretty mundane.
想不通为什么有人把他们作为目标
I mean, I couldn't figure out why anyone would target them.
219  东五十三大街
但地下室的租户
But the basement tenant
是美国印铸局
is the United States Bureau of Engraving and Printing.
我知道那地方
Oh, I know that location.
银行将污损钞票送到那里
It's where banks send soiled and defaced bills.
没错  残钞部
Exactly. The Department of Mutilated Money.
纽约办公室处理整个东北部的残钞
And the New York office handles the entire northeast.
你能想象那里有多少钞票吗
I mean, do you know how much cash they must have in there?
但不能流通  是等待被销毁的
Yeah, but it's unusable currency, waiting to be destroyed.
不是所有都会被销毁  很大一部分
Not all of it. A good fraction of it
可以被清洗修复
can be cleaned and repaired.
路易斯·瓦格斯  前几天被杀的一名保安
A security guard, Luis Vargas, was killed the other day,
很可能就是被偷设计图的人所杀
presumably by whoever was stealing the blueprints for this address.
你知道在那名保安身上发现什么了吗
And do you know what they found on his body?
与造成停电相同的细菌
The same bacterium that's causing the blackout,
只不过路易斯·瓦格斯
except Luis Vargas was killed
是在流星雨到达纽约的前一天被害
a full day before the meteor shower hit New York.
你觉得细菌来自别的外星物种入侵
So you think the bacteria came from some other alien invasion?
虽然我不想承认
As much as I hate to admit it,
但我觉得那可能根本不是外星物种
I think it might not be alien at all.
他们说它跟已知细菌相似
I mean, they say it's similar to known bacteria.
如果是有人培养了新的菌株
So what if someone cultivated a new strain
然后释放并导致停电
and released it to cause a blackout?
这可是窃取钞票的完美掩护
It's the perfect cover to steal a bunch of cash.
残钞
Yeah, mutilated cash.
那为什么不抢银行
Why not hit a bank?
因为这更容易
Because it's an easier target.
大部分人认为那些钱基本等同于垃圾
I mean, people think that money's basically trash,
也就是说  大部分人根本不会想到
which means people wouldn't think
先去那里查看  但我们想到了
to look there first, but we did.
如果我们能过去看看
And if we can just get over there,
也许就能阻止盗窃案的发生
we might be able to stop the heist from happening
-并找到造成大范围停电的元凶  -没错
- and find the people responsible for the whole blackout. - Yeah.
说是我们  其实只有你
And by we, I mean you,
因为我们现在仍在这里隔离
because we're still kind of quarantined here.
好的  我看看我能做些什么
All right, I'll see what I can do.
能把手机还我吗
Can I have that?
这到底是什么
What the hell is this?
-能把手机还我了吗  -不
- Can I have my phone, please? - No.
这到底是什么
What the hell is this?
这是谁发给你的
Who-who sent this to you?
一名探员被派去搜查
An agent sent to search
你所居住的政府房产
the government property where you're living
发现了你藏在黑胶唱片中的疑似NZT药片
for what looks like NZT pills hidden in your vinyl collection.
你跟我说没有多的了
You told me there weren't any more.
派人去搜查我的公寓前
You know, you could've said something to me
你本可以跟我说一声的
before sending the cavalry into my apartment.
我确实说了  可你骗了我
I did say something, and you lied to me.
你到底知不知道随心所欲地使用药物
Do you have any idea how irresponsible it is
有多么不负责任
to use this drug however you want, whenever you want?
这些规矩  监管你的药量
The rules, managing your dosage,
派人保护你的安全
keeping a watch out for you--
都是为了保证你的生命安全
they're there to keep you alive, to keep you safe.
得了吧  联调局才不在意我的安全
Oh, come on! The FBI doesn't care about keeping me safe.
他们只在意我能发挥作用
They care about keeping me useful.
布莱恩  如果你认为我不在乎
Brian, if you think that I don't care,
那你就从未用心
then you haven't been paying attention.
我带你进的联调局
I brought you into the FBI,
-一直支持你  -别说了别说了
- I've stood up for you - Don't, don't, don't, don't.
-次数多得数不过来  -你根本不知道
- more times than I can count. - You have no idea
-如果事情无法控制  -你在说什么
- I know what happens - what you're talking about here.
-我知道会发生什么  -我跟别人不一样
- if this gets out of hand. - I'm not like anyone.
没有人跟我的经历一样
No one else is going through what I am going through.
你像个瘾君子一样私藏药片  布莱恩
You are hiding pills like an addict, Brian.
我知道你对NZT的副作用免疫
I know that you are immune to NZT side effects,
也知道那让你觉得自己与众不同
and I know that makes you think that you're different somehow,
但你并不能免疫
but you are not immune.
你是在告诉我  我现在怎么想吗
You're gonna tell me what I think right now?
我不是那个意思
I'm not... That's not what I'm saying.
不  因为你根本不知道我的想法  丽贝卡
No, 'cause you don't know inside my head, Rebecca.
我们没有心有灵犀  知道吗
We're not psychic twins, okay?
如果你想听实话
And if you want the real truth,
也许我是对药物上瘾
I may be addicted to these drugs.
顺便谢谢你
Thanks for that, by the way.
但你对我上瘾了
But you're addicted to me.
-解决问题  -什么
- Solving things, - What?
破案  这些让你上瘾
breaking cases, that's your high.
而正因有我  你才能做得顺风顺水
And because of me, you get to do it at a whole new level.
怎么  你想回到过去的生活吗
What, you want to go back to your old life?
处理文书工作
Keeping up with paperwork
事无巨细  谨慎小心
and crossing your T's and dotting your I's,
再看着一切以失望告终
seeing it all end in frustration,
至少一半时间是这样吧
what, like, half the time?
你跟我一样需要这个
You need all this as much as I do.
你跟我一样需要NZT  你心里明白
You need NZT as much as I do, and you know it.
能把手机还给我了吗
Can I have my phone?
私藏NZT药片  4粒
还有两粒
Two pills.
私藏NZT药片  2粒
他们只找到两粒
They only found two.
剩下的呢
Where are the others?
爸爸看上去很紧张
Dad looks stressed.
也不能怪他
Well, can you blame him?
先是停电了
First there's the power outage.
现在联邦探员又出现在我们家
Now we have federal agents in the living room,
进行尴尬的对话
making awkward conversation.
是啊
Yeah.
也许他只是发现了你跟
Or maybe he's just picking up on the glances
那个长得像加里·格兰特的探员眉来眼去
between you and the one who looks like Cary Grant.
-妈妈  -好吧
- Mom. - Well,
我就那么一说  瑞秋  别装了
I'm just saying, Rachel, come on.
他对你的迷恋全写在他脸上了
That boy is smitten, it's written all over his face.
拜托别再说了
Please stop talking.
下巴方正  头发茂盛
Square jaw, still has all his hair.
我对天发誓  我会拿这把奶油刀割腕的
I swear to God, I will cut my wrist with this butter knife.
好吧  你有心事
All right, so something is on your mind.
如果跟他无关  那你在想什么
If it's not him, what is it?
别跟爸爸说好吗
Don't tell Dad, okay?
他会生气的
He gets so upset about these things.
是布莱恩的事
It's Brian.
我们那天晚上在他的安全屋里玩
We were hanging out at his safe house the other night,
然后他去拿他的唱片
and he went over to his records,
似乎从唱片拿出某样东西
and it looked like he took something out.
等他离开以后  我过去找
So when he left, I went over...
然后发现
...and I found...
我不知道这是什么
I'm not sure what they are,
但我很确定  他变成现在这样
but I'm pretty sure that they are part of why he is
部分原因是这些药
the way that he is now.
但真正让我困扰的是
But what's really bothering me is...
他因为吃这些药才进入联调局吗
did he get into the FBI because he's taking these?
还是这些药是联调局给他的
Or are they the ones that are giving it to him?
我从没看过这种东西
I've never seen anything like this.
你们还好吗
You okay?
爸爸
Hey, Dad.
好  好  很好
Yes, yes. Good, um...
我帮你摆午餐好吗
Here, let me help you put out lunch, okay?
好啊
Okay, good.
他们洗劫一空
They cleaned house.
里面没一分钱了
Not a dollar inside?
只剩不能用的钞票  能用的都拿走了
Not one you can spend. Cleaned out.
看来你的想法是对的
Looks like you had the right idea.
只是我们没有及时赶到
We just didn't get here in time.
所以这是盗窃案  罪犯知道会停电
So it was a heist, and they did know the blackout was coming.
我跟残钞部的高级经理谈过了
Well, I talked to the department's senior manager.
他估计保险箱里
The guy estimates there was
原有超过八百万美金
a little more than $8 million in this safe.
鲍伊  我之后再打给你
Boyle, I have to call you back.
-看来疾控中心似乎有进展  -好
- Looks like the CDC might have an update. - All right.
丽贝卡·哈里斯探员  布莱恩·芬奇
Agent Rebecca Harris, Brian Finch.
你们不是应该戴面罩之类的吗
Aren't you guys supposed to be wearing masks or something?
细菌被证明无传染性
The bacterium proved non-communicable.
看来它只以非生物来源的电子为食
Seems it feeds exclusively on electrons found in inanimate sources.
意思是我们根本不该被隔离
Meaning we didn't have to be here in the first place?
你们可以走了
You're free to go.
但我们先得测体征
Well, after we take your vitals.
这是法律规定
Legal issue.
证明我们将你们健康送回家
Proof we sent you home in good health.
你可以离开了
You're discharged.
丽贝卡
Hey, Rebecca?
我们能拿回自己的衣服吧
We get our clothes back, right?
玛丽
Marie.
玛丽  别弄了
Marie, stop.
过来
Come here.
坐下  跟我说说话
Sit down, talk to me.
你在想什么
What's on your mind?
你比我更常跟布莱恩谈话
You talk to Brian more than I do.
他总是找你解决问题  信任你
He's always sought you out, trusted you.
丹尼斯  我知道你跟他
Dennis, I know that you have been
讨论过这一切
talking to him about all this, all right?
我也理解你想隐瞒这些事情
And I understand if you want to keep it close to the vest,
只有你确定他没事
and you wouldn't do that if you didn't know
你才会这样做
that he was all right.
但布莱恩真的没事吗
But is Brian all right?
什么意思
What do you mean?
我的意思是  他们对他做了什么
I mean, what are they doing to him?
你知道吗
Do you know?
他很好
He's fine.
布莱恩不会有事的
Brian's gonna be all right.
你知道他们给他药片什么的吗
Do you know anything about pills or drugs they're giving him?
你知道什么了
What do you know?
看来你在认真工作
Hard at work, I see.
是啊
Yeah.
你还好吗
You okay?
当然
Yeah.
我有点不爽疾控中心
I mean, I'm a little bummed
烧掉我的快乐分裂乐队的T恤
that the CDC burned my Joy Division shirt.
那是原版的
It was an original.
你见到丽贝卡了吗
You seen Rebecca?
她跟纳兹在楼上
She's upstairs with Naz.
你俩之间在隔离时发生了什么吧
Something happen between you two, in quarantine?
说不清楚  做了错事  说了错话
I don't know, mistakes were made, words were said.
这应该是我们第一次真正吵架
I guess it's our first real fight.
联络人与顾问的关系本来就够有压力了
The handler-consultant relationship is stressful enough
更何况你们一起被关在塑料房里
without being thrown into a plastic bubble together.
你们会没事的
You guys will get through it.
-好吗  -好
- Okay? - Yeah.
发电机跟手机信号塔开始断电了
Generators and cell towers are starting to power down.
我告诉纳兹我下来看看你有没有发现
I told Naz I'd come down, check in to see if you had any leads
关于残钞抢匪的线索
on the mutilated money gang.
我的确有些线索
Yeah, I do have something.
我认为进行盗窃的人
So my theory is that whoever pulled off the heist
就是传播细菌的人  对吧
planted the bacteria, right?
因为金融区是最先停电的区域
And since the Financial District was the first to lose power,
特别是钱伯斯街的两百区
specifically the 200 block of Chambers Street,
可以假设那里是细菌最先开始散播的地方
we can assume that's where the bacteria was first introduced.
至于是谁做了这件事
Now, as for who did it,
你见过这些科学家吗
纽约只有十二个人
there are only 12 people in the New York area
有足够的科学专业知识
with enough scientific expertise
既能设计细菌
to not only engineer the bacteria,
又知道如何成功传播
but also know how to successfully plant it.
如果他们够聪明  能做这些事
Now, if they were smart enough to do all that,
那他们大概也够聪明
then they're probably smart enough
知道躲开监控摄影机
to stay off security cameras.
这时就该用上这些了
And that's where these come in.
我尊重你的一些方法  芬奇
Well, I've come to respect some of your ways, Finch,
但不代表
that doesn't mean that
我愿意挂着广告牌在金融区
I'm gonna be strolling around the Financial District
四处闲晃
wearing a sandwich board.
那个区域有很多流浪者
There's a large homeless population around that area,
断电时无处可去的人
people who have nowhere to go during a blackout.
他们或许能认出罪犯
They might be able to identify one of the perps.
或者我打个电话给国安局的朋友
Or I could just call a friend at the NSA.
不行
We're not doing that.
为什么
Why not?
就是  他们应该备份了
Yeah, they would have a copy
这些科学家所有的通话记录
of every phone conversation these scientists have had.
是偷偷地去做
Well, is this on the DL
还是得遵照《爱国者法案》
or are we asserting the Patriot Act?
你居然支持保护公民隐私
You're siding to protect people's privacy?
真讽刺
That's ironic.
不管是不是盗窃案
Heist or not,
有人切断了曼哈顿的电力
someone shut down the power on Manhattan.
这是恐怖主义行为
That's an act of terrorism.
要不你挂着这个牌子去问
Or you can wear the sandwich board.
反正他是你的顾问
He's your consultant.
其实我打算多做几个的
Actually, I was gonna make a few.
我们都可以挂起来
I thought we could all wear them.
不用了  你说得对  鲍伊
No, you're right, Boyle.
应该联系国安局
We should call in the NSA.
布莱恩  我能和你单独谈谈吗
Brian, can I talk to you for a second?
行
Yeah.
抱歉...
Look, I'm sorry...
你还记得吗  这一切开始的时候
You know, when all of this started,
我们向彼此保证过
we made promises to each other.
我说过  无论发生什么事我都会帮你
I said I would help you through anything
只要你不对我说谎
as long as you didn't lie to me.
我知道  我不是故意骗你的
I know. I didn't mean to lie to you.
我刚刚和纳兹谈过
I just spoke to Naz.
她会给你分配一个新联络人
You're being assigned to a different handler,
在此之前  你跟着鲍伊
and in the meantime, you'll work with Boyle.
国安局进入刑司委的那一瞬间
Of course the day the NSA came to the CJC
一切都失控了
was the day everything started spiraling out of control.
你知道吗  这么多年来国安局一直声称
You know how for years the NSA's been saying
他们只收集电话通讯的元数据
they only collect metadata from phone conversations?
真相并非如此
Well, that's sort of a lie.
请不要碰
Don't handle that, please.
其实他们记录和存储了
They're actually recording and storing
至少百分之八十美国人的语音通讯
the audio of at least 80% of Americans' phone calls.
在这里签字
Sign here.
可以碰吗
Can I touch?
成年人每天平均接打五个电话
The average adult sends and receives about five calls a day.
乘以三百六十五天  再乘以十二个嫌疑人
Multiply that by 365 days, times 12 suspects,
我要听超过两万一千通电话
I'm listening to over 21,000 conversations.
这其中大多与案件毫不相关
Most of them were totally irrelevant.
我早说了别逼走她
I told you not to push her away.
别紧张  你什么也不必说
Relax, you don't have to say anything.
新的联络人  不是吧
A new handler? Really?
你觉得这样你就能搞定了吗
You think you're gonna be able to make that work?
这里还有谁会像她那样保护你
Is there anyone else here who will protect you like she did?
你打算怎么解决
How are you going to fix this?
我解决不了
I can't.
能不能...
Ma... uh...
刚才那通我没听清  能不能...
I can't... I can't make out this last track. If you...
对  回放一下  谢谢
Yeah, rewind that. Thank you.
说到哪儿了  对了
Where was I? Right.
范围缩小到伊恩·马歇尔和斯特金·里德
It's down to Ian Marshall and Sturgeon Reid.
我并不反对你的观点  只是我们识别不出来
即使真有外星人在给我们制造麻烦
人类还没有准备好
或许在我们孙辈那一代能实现
但我们有生之年做不到
敢不敢打个赌
我赌一美元能在有生之年
One dollar says we will find evidence
发现外星生物存在的证据
of alien life in our lifetime.
我赌一美元发现不了
And one dollar says we won't.
我觉得你欠马歇尔博士一美元  里德博士
I believe you owe Dr. Marshall a dollar, Dr. Reid.
这是怎么回事
What is this?
我们这是在干什么
What are we doing here?
你们两个进行了一场朋友间的较量
You two have kind of a friendly rivalry.
算是吧
Ish.
两位著名的天体物理学家
Just a couple of eminent astrophysicists
争论我们能否在将来几十年内
debating whether or not we discover evidence
发现外星生物的踪迹
of extraterrestrial life within the next couple of decades.
你们甚至还为此打了个赌  是吧
You even made a bet about it, didn't you?
赌注一美元
For one dollar.
你怎么会知道这事
How could you possibly know that?
一边是多疑的斯特金·里德
On the one hand, we have the skeptic Sturgeon Reid.
一边是把金钱和自尊押在外星人身上的
Laying his money and pride on the ETs,
伊恩·马歇尔博士
Dr. Ian Marshall.
你决心要赢这一美元  是吧
And you saw to it you were gonna win that buck, didn't you?
我并没有承认
Uh, I'm not conceding that
有过这样的赌约
such a bet even happened.
不需要你承认
We don't need you to.
我们向沃尔科特大学的教务长
Uh, we shared our concerns
表达了我们的疑虑
with the provost of Walcott University,
她允许我们进你的实验室看一看
and she agreed to let us take a look in your lab.
我们发现了微量导致断电的细菌
We found trace amounts of the bacteria causing the outages,
和一些毁掉的培养菌
some destroyed cultures.
有什么解释吗
Care to explain?
我来帮你起个头
I'll get you started.
你发现了一种专门以电子为食的细菌
You discovered a species of bacteria that feeds on electrons,
但是你没有公开
but you kept it to yourself.
你在金融区释放了菌落
You released a colony in the Financial District
而且是趁流星雨到来之际释放
and timed that release with the passage of the meteor shower,
这样人们就会联想到外星人
so people would start thinking aliens.
这计划挺聪明的  兄弟  别谦虚
It's a clever plan, dude, own it.
而且我们逮了你个正着  所以...
Plus we already got you kind of dead to rights, so...
其实  是我手下一位助理研究员
Actually, it was one of my research assistants
发现了这种细菌
who discovered the bacteria,
但我说服她不要公布这一发现
but I convinced her not to report it.
我只是想赢
I-I just wanted to win.
在某一瞬间  你不再满足于此
And at some point you started to want more than that.
你说什么
I'm sorry?
从残钞部
The theft of $8 million
盗取八百万美元
from the Department of Mutilated Money.
路易斯·瓦格斯  两天前被你杀害的那个保安
Luis Vargas, the security guard you murdered two nights ago.
你引发了断电
You caused the blackout,
又以此为掩护大发横财
then used it as cover to make yourself rich.
你在偷设计图的时候被他发现了
He surprised you when you were stealing the plans.
不  不  不
No, no, no, no, no.
我没有杀人
I am not a killer.
我不是小偷
I-I'm not a thief.
我是终身教授
I have tenure.
两晚前吗
Two nights ago?
这起谋杀案什么时候发生的
What time did this murder happen?
死亡时间估计是在九点到十一点
Time of death is estimated between 9:00 and 11:00 P.M.
别慌  伊恩
Relax, Ian.
周二晚上我和马歇尔博士在哥伦比亚大学
Tuesday night, Dr. Marshall and I gave a lecture
开了场联合讲座
together at Columbia.
一千四百名学生可以替我们作证
1,400 students will attest for our whereabouts.
马歇尔博士也许释放了细菌
Uh, he may have planted the bacteria...
但他绝对没谋杀任何人
but Dr. Marshall didn't kill anyone.
请避开豪特大道与格兰大道以及
Please avoid all streets between Hoten and Grand,
艾伦大道与东河之间所有街道
Allen and the East River.
政府官员已重新开通威廉斯堡大桥
City officials has reopened the Williamsburg Bridge
-也重建了检查站  -拜托
- and a checkpoint has been reestablished, - Come on.
-因此造成严重交通堵塞  -拜托
- causing major traffic delays. - Come on. Come on.
两位好
Hey, guys.
你们还好吗
How's it going?
这问题真蠢  当然不好
Oh, that's a dumb question. It's not going.
因为路被堵住了  对吧
That's the thing about standstill traffic, right?
真是难受啊
It's the pits.
你是寇依·马丁逊
Corey Martinson?
你就是伊恩·马歇尔的研究助理吧
You're Ian Marshall's research assistant.
当你默认了
I'll take that as a yes.
我们是联调局的人
So we're from the FBI
我们得知你的老板是此次
and we just learned that your boss is the one
城市瘫痪的始作俑者
behind the hoax that paralyzed the city.
据他所说
And the way he tells it,
你帮他培育出了细菌
you helped him fabricate the bacteria that did it.
他还说  你是他唯一的搭档
Also, he said you were his only partner.
请问你是否愿意作出
Would you be willing to testify
对你老板不利的证明呢
against your boss in the charges he faces?
我不知道
Um... I don't know.
慢着  你们怎么知道我在这儿
Wait, how did you find me here?
这里  我们只是在等你露面
Here? Oh, we just waited for you to show up.
你懂吧  毕竟
I mean, this is, after all,
这是现在出城的唯一道路
the only way out of the city at the moment.
当然  联调局做了点手脚
We at the FBI kind of set it up that way.
重点是
Thing is,
有人想趁着此次城市断电事件
somebody used the blackout to stage a robbery
盗窃残钞部的财产
of the Department of Mutilated Money.
比如某个  怎么说呢  薪水过低
Someone, like, say, an underpaid research assistant
学生债务缠身的研究助理
with crushing amounts of student debt.
此人将老板的小小恶作剧当作自己的机会
Someone who saw her boss' relatively harmless hoax as an opportunity.
这个人的表亲
That same somebody had a cousin
还因持械抢劫坐过牢
who did time for armed robbery.
你好  弗兰克
Hi, Frank.
他们合伙想出了一个办法
Together, they came up with a plan
于是从亚马逊网站上订购了
and they even ordered a ridiculous amount
一大堆洗衣粉以及化学溶剂
of laundry detergents and solvents from Amazon
用来清洁他们偷的钱
to clean the money they stole.
这话听着熟悉吗
Any of this sounding familiar?
想否认吧
Of course not.
你们俩不介意我们打开救护车的后门看一看吧
Now, would you two mind if we took a look in the back of this ambulance,
不用说  车是从私人紧急医疗服务租的
no doubt rented from a private EMS service
以便隔离期间可以自由行动
to move about freely in the quarantine?
谢了
Thank you.
我们没拿到逮捕令
We weren't able to get a warrant,
因为停电了
with all the power being out.
但你试图逃跑倒是给了我合理理由
But that attempted escape is probable cause.
而朋友  那些就是铁证
And that, my friend, is irrefutable evidence.
想要美好时光
请拨打电话
上面写的什么
What's it say?
你说有没有人试图拨这个电话
I wonder if anyone's ever tried calling this number.
憧憬着电话另一边就是美好时光
Think there's actually a good time at the end of this line?
你说呢  打打看
Huh? Should we call?
你想的话可以打打看
You can give it a shot if you want.
我要回家了  兄弟
I'm gonna go home, man.
布莱恩
Hey, Brian.
我本来不想说的...
Pains me to say it, but, uh...
这样也不算最糟  是吧
it's not the worst thing, huh?
我俩一起工作
Us working together?
其实我并不是真想回家
I didn't really want to go home.
但我绝对不想回刑司委
I sure as hell didn't want to go back to the CJC.
我只想到一个可以去的地方
There's only one place I could think to go,
一个还有人爱我的地方
the one place people still love me.
因为他们没有其他选择
Because they have no choice.
卡梅隆
Hey, Cameron.
你这就要走吗
You leaving already?
我还想着和你们吃完饭呢
I was hoping to catch you guys for dinner.
是啊  听说电力很快就会恢复
Yeah, we heard it shouldn't be long before the power's restored.
如果我是你  我会马上离开
Hey, if I were you, I'd turn around now.
什么  为什么
What? Why?
虽然我不知道发生了什么
I don't know what's going on,
但我绝对听到他们提到了你
but I definitely heard your name.
能跑则跑吧
So run while you can.
你们好啊
Hey, guys.
发生了什么
What's going on?
坐下  布莱恩
Sit down, Brian.
好吧
Okay.
有种不详的预感
That sounds ominous.
妈
Mom?
你还好吧
Are you okay?
要知道  布莱恩...
You know, Brian...
我一直相信你有过人之处
I always knew that you had something special about you.
心地善良
A good heart.
体贴  关心他人
You were sensitive, you cared about other people.
就算你一时冲动
Even if you were being impulsive,
就算你做的事情
even if the things you were doing
看上去很自私
looked selfish on the face of it.
正因为我深信你身上的闪光点
I believed in that light that was in you so much that, uh,
导致我忽略了很多事
I let a lot of things slip by.
当我如往常一样
Finding pot in your jeans
洗你留下的裤子时发现了大麻
when you left them out for me to wash as usual.
妈  听我说...
Mom, come on...
不  让我说完
No. Let me finish.
我想我们也许能
I figured that we would find
找到某种平衡点  你懂吗
some kind of balance, you know?
你爸会约束你  限制你
Your father would give you discipline, some structure;
我会给你空间去折腾
I would give you room to run
这样你就能自己想通
so you could figure things out.
而且我真的觉得
And I honestly thought
那正是你现在的状态
that's what was happening to you now.
我原以为  也许他终于想明白了
I thought, maybe he's finally figured it out.
我真是个傻瓜
Ugh. What an idiot I was.
别这么说  妈  你...
Come on, Mom, you...
不
No.
-这些到底是什么  -天啊
- What the hell are these? - Geez.
你想告诉我它们是什么吗
You want to tell me about them?
因为你爸不肯说
Because your father won't.
我们结婚四十二年了
We've been married for 42 years
没有什么事
and there has never been a single thing
是我们不能谈论的
that we could not discuss.
所以不管这些是什么  问题一定很严重
So whatever these are must be serious.
爸
Dad.
别叫我  这是你和你妈之间的事
Oh, no. This is between you and your mother.
你把这些东西带回咱们家
You brought this into our home.
不  我没有  我没有
No, I didn't. No, I didn't.
从你把妹妹卷进去的那一刻起
The moment you got your sister into this,
你就做错了
you did.
到处乱放这些药片
Leaving these pills lying around,
让她去你那间
having her come to that safe house
被神秘赠与的安全屋
that you have been mysteriously given.
你把你妹妹置于危险中
You put your sister in danger.
不  我没有
No, I haven't.
卧底去了你那里
Undercover agents coming over,
在餐桌上失血致死
bleeding out on the kitchen table.
瑞秋
Rachel.
布莱恩  住嘴
Brian, no.
我不会再睁一只眼闭一只眼了
I am not turning a blind eye anymore.
我不知道这些药片是什么
I don't know what these pills are.
我也不想知道
I don't want to know.
我们一家已经卷进来了
And I don't want our family any deeper in this
我不想我们陷得更深
than we already are.
私藏NZT药片  2粒
私藏NZT药片  0粒
妈
Mom...
我不能把一切都告诉你  但我可以解释
I can't tell you everything, but I can explain...
布莱恩  别说了  我不需要任何借口
Brian, no. I don't want any more excuses.
因为除非你开始做出不同的选择
Because unless you start making some different choices,
否则这里不欢迎你
you are not welcome here.
我爱你  布莱恩  可是...
I love you, Brian, but...
我...
just...
这样不行
no.
*纸杯之船*
*Paper cup of the boat*
*起伏的海浪*
*Heaving chest of the sea*
*载着我们俩*
*Carry both of us*
*载着她  也载着我*
*Carry her, carry me*
*从我们出生的地方*
*From the place we were born*
*去向自由之地*
*To the land of the free*
*载着我们俩*
*Carry both of us*
*载着她  也载着我*
*Carry her, carry me*
*轻启她的唇*
*Moving silent her lips*
*在那月光下*
*By the moon's only light*
*播散银色祝祷*
*Sowing silver prayers*
*在一片夜色中*
*In the blanket of night.*
快去拦住她
Just go do it.
在这儿干坐着  你也不会更好过
It ain't gonna get any easier, you sitting here.
我知道  可是...
I-I know. - It just...
她要走了  快去
You're gonna miss her. Go.
快下车
Get out of the car!
瑞秋
Rachel.
听我说...
Listen...
杰森  很抱歉
Jason, I'm sorry.
我...  我该保持联络的
I... I should've stayed in touch.
我知道  我在父母家对你表现得怪怪的
And I was weird to you at my parents', I know.
因为事情变得有点奇怪
It's just, things have been strange.
我来不是谈这个的
I'm not here to talk about that.
好吧
Oh, okay.
你母亲提到一个卧底
Your mom mentioned an undercover agent,
他出现在布莱恩的公寓  险些失血而死
that he showed up at Brian's apartment, bleeding out.
是啊
Yeah?
你能给我描述一下这个人吗
Could you describe him for me?
今天这么安逸
Banker's hours today?
是F地铁  有些晚点了
"F" Train, there was some kind of delay.
我得跟布莱恩谈谈
I need to talk to Brian.
还没来
Not in yet.
估计他跟你搭同一地铁
I guess he took the same train.
我现在接不了电话
I can't come to the phone right now,
如果有急事
but if this is an emergency,
你可以随时联系丽贝卡·哈里斯
you can try Rebecca Harris, any time.
丽贝卡
本想过来找你
Thought about stopping by,
可我觉得你最近见我够多了
but I figured you'd seen enough of me lately.
你应该知道一些事
You should know a few things.
未接电话
丽贝卡·哈里斯
很抱歉我说了那些话
I'm sorry for the things I said.
我没理由那么说你
You deserve better than that.
无论发生什么事
Whatever else happens,
你在我身上看到从没人发觉的潜能
you saw potential in me that no one else ever did.
改变我人生的不仅仅是那种药  还有你
It's not just the pill that changed my life, it's you.
所以  谢谢你
So, thanks for that.
事情暂时可能会有点疯狂
Things may get a little crazy for a while.
我知道你对我的付出
I know I haven't given back
我还没有给予同样的回报
as much as you've given me.
也许我永远都做不到
There's probably no way I ever could.
但从现在开始  我要试一试
But starting now, I'm going to try.
为了尝试
And in order to try,
我必须做一些事
I've got to do a few things.
所以你可能短期内联系不到我
So you may not hear from me for a minute.
私藏NZT药片  0粒
我想我有办法把事情搞定
I think I have a way to make some of this okay.
私藏NZT药片  2粒
如果一切顺利  过几天我就能见到你
And if it all works out, I'll see you in a few days.
如果不顺利  那...
And if it doesn't? Well...
至少我们开心过  是吧
we had some lulz, right?